

Software Developer



•	standingwater.io
•	blog.standingwater.io
C	malan88
伽	malan88

WHOIAM

I prefer Python, but I wear many hats. I have written code in C#, Python, vanilla JavaScript, and ReactJS. I have dabbled in C, Scheme, C++, and Bash. I have built static sites in GatsbyJS, interfaces in WPF, and web scrapers and bots in Python. I even built an arduino-based PID controller for a popcorn popper to roast my own coffee. But by far most of my time has been spent developing a single web technology, consisting of \approx 14,000 lines of code in Python, Flask, and SQLAlchemy, in the pursuit of my obsession with literature: anno.wiki.

EXPERIENCE

2017 - 2019 Intertextual Canon Cloud (anno.wiki)

Flask App

The ICC is a web application designed to allow for collaboratively building an exhaustive and definitive repository of annotated literature. I designed, developed, deployed, and continue to maintain the project solo, managing occasionally to rope in some programmer friends for help with various features. It consists of \approx 14k lines of code and \approx 100k lines of code churn. The backend uses Flask/SQLAlchemy. The frontend uses Jinja2, Sass, and VanillaJS. I also had to write several ETL data pipelines for processing Project Gutenberg texts. It is deployed via Heroku. I learned the entire web application life cycle on this project, and it continues to teach me. It is currently maintained at https://anno.wiki.

Python / Flask / SQLAlchemy / MariaDB / Elasticsearch / pytest / Heroku

2019 - Current Intertextual Canon Cloud 2

Flask/React App

This is the second iteration of the ICC, with improved data architecture and a single-page application front end based in React. Using Elasticsearch to store texts and PostgreSQL to store annotations and general application data allows for faster incremental searching. I also wrote more sophisticated text processors for breaking text into 100k byte chunks and annotating stylistic elements, while stripping all styling from the raw text.

Python / Flask / SQLAlchemy / Elasticsearch / PostgreSQL / Docker / Auth0 /

 ${\tt ReactJS}$

2020 - Current Euler Sciences LLC

Contract Developer

I worked on a GUI interface for laser system meant to treat skin conditions. I also developed the company website in GatsbyJS (and did the graphical work myself in Photoshop).

C# / Windows Presentation Foundation / SQLite / Photoshop / GatsbyJS

2020 - Current Healt

Healthy Brands, LLC

Contract Developer

I've worked on several projects for this company: a multithreaded scraper and alert system for notifying the company of BuyBox loss events on Amazon, I launched and modified a Django-based question and answer forum from biostars, prepared and maintained several VPS servers, one in Arch Linux, designed and maintained several WordPress sites, integrated Twilio into the company's ZOHO CRM software, and modified several Shopify templates.

Python / BeautifulSoup4 / Zoho / Twilio / WordPress / Shopify

2019 Minimal Pairs Scraping Project

Scraper

I generated an Anki deck for recognizing French phonemes difficult to hear for an American English speaker using "minimal pairs," words in French which differ by only one phoneme. Limit for requests was 500 per day, had to save progress and download the data over several days.

Python / requests / BeautifulSoup4 / json / csv

EDUCATION

2008 – 2010 Philosophy and Classics

Florida State University

University of South Florida

Focus on Ancient Philosophy, particularly Aristotle, Philosphy of Mind, and Symbolic Logic. Ancient Greek and Latin. President of Philosophy Club (2010)

2007 – 2008 Philosophy

General introductory classes, Social Philosophy, Critical Thinking

LANGUAGES

FREE TIME

CLOSING ARGUMENT

English — native, French — fluent, Spanish — rudimentary I love high culture. Coffee, wine, cheese, cocktails, literature, music, art, cinema, science; anything that makes life worth living. And running.

I have had enough experience learning new things to have full confidence in my ability to learn new things.